hey everyone
welcome to week
of
octave textbook group cohort one
we are in the review and synthesis
weeks
it's been a great
three-month-ish
journey
and it doesn't stop here but we'll go
over that so
two
points of process for those who are here
live and of course re-watching
and then we'll move to the more
conceptual parts
so first
in the onboarding page
you'll see these two columns the two
columns are rsvping yes to join cohort
two part one going through chapters one
through five if you would like to for a
second time
many people will be just doing it
for fun or for learning or however they
want and also there's the opportunity to
continue on with the second half of the
textbook
which is going to get into a lot of the
hands-on modeling
and we'll be especially looking forward
to developing a lot of the notebooks and
interactive formats that'll help us get
a lot of understanding there
um so please check
yes
for whichever
row your name is in for whether you
would like to continue on with part two
as well as
retake uh part one as well
you'd be welcome to be just a
participant
and also feel free to get in touch if
you are interested in taking some other
roles such as like facilitating or
scaffolding some aspect but we can
talk more about that for those who are
interested so
point one go to the onboarding list and
continue on
however you want
second point um if you go to future
textbook groups page
you'll see an embedded form
as well as a link to the form if you
want it in a new window like that
this would be
exceptionally requested and helpful
for you to provide some evaluations
numerically and as short or as long as
you want
on providing feedback
those are
one way that you can provide feedback
anonymously
the second way
is uh building on some of the ideas that
people are already adding here this is
an editable page so people can
add thoughts
as they see fit about like what would be
awesome for future textbook groups
or any other feedback or as always they
can email active inference
activeinference.gmail.com if they want
like a response to any specific points
um and then also it's provided here at
the link to share for people who want to
join future cohorts so that link will be
like getting people
onboarded into the next cohort which is
september 2022 in this case but
this is going to be like an evergreen
form
that will just continue to have a list
of people who expressed interest and be
on boarding them into
subsequent cohorts of which will begin
several per year
going forward
any
uh and next week we'll be talking more
about the feedback
specifically
and about projects
and about carrying on
today is like a little bit of a more
conceptual synthesis and review
and again next week will be more like
logistical
um and project oriented review so just
on these points or anything else
does anyone want to just raise their
hand or unmute and share anything that
they like
okay
let us
conceptually review
then
um
we read the first five chapters of the
active inference textbook
does anyone have overall thoughts that
they'd like to provide at the
five chapter scale
then we're going to go into a chapter
scale
then we'll be continuing to
dive in as um granularly as required
but at the scale of the first five
chapters you can see them here on this
preface page
as well as here in the chapters list
as a unit of five
chapters
what were people's sense
how did it update yes please ben
and then only
well i was just going to say i think um
you know as i've said to people before i
think
coming from a non-mathematics background
i thought that these chapters were
really accessible in terms of the kind
of conceptual
uh things that they were putting on the
table but i i just wondered what other
people's opinions were in terms of
um
you know
understanding the conceptual toolkit of
active inference
before you've built up a kind of
mathematical understanding
um because i'm about to start kind of um
learning some of the mathematics behind
it and i wondered what people thought of
like
the the potential to fully grasp these
concepts without the mathematics and
what the relationship between the two
might be i'm just curious what other
people think about that i guess
thanks great question um ali and then
mike and then anyone else who wants to
chime in
yeah it was a pretty exciting journey
for me uh but
i'll definitely need to
read over all those five chapters once
again at least once again uh in order to
grasp uh more fully uh the contents of
those chapters uh uh my own
personal opinion about uh
the way materials uh is organized in
these uh the first part of the textbook
is
uh
uh i couldn't see a kind of um
hierarchical or uh
i don't know structural uh
organization for these chapters as much
as i i like to see them because um
sometimes uh
they delve into a theoretical uh
theoretical aspect of all the things
much more deeply than the mathematical
side and sometimes it's vice versa
but
i i think that if it was
organized in a way that
as ben mentioned we can go from a
firm found a firm
conceptual foundation into
the granular formalism and mathematics
uh
at least for me that would be
much more uh accessible and much more uh
i would be able to organize the
materials in a coherent much more
coherent way in my mind so uh one thing
uh that um i really enjoyed about uh
these chapters is uh the
uh
kind of uh
you see uh
a kind of uh the vision it uh
[Music]
tries to
put forward uh regarding the future uh
possible research uh and also uh things
especially in chapter five uh and the
the path that can be taken from this
point on
thank you
mike and then anyone else
yeah i'll pick up from where ali left
off i think it's
um
somewhat remarkable that they were able
to fit everything they did into those
first five chapters
and understanding
they probably had some
idea of how much space they wanted in
that part of the book before getting
into the the practical or applied
components in part two
you know the the high road low road
contrast and
um
sort of coming at the problem from
two different angles i think was useful
um
like ben i found the math to be
generally accessible although i confess
i i think i still go through this sort
of pattern where
i feel like i get it and i have this
intuitive understanding of it but then
there are things where
uh i sort of bog down and
looking at some of the mathematical
details or
some of the graphical representations um
related to things like message passing
um
have to slow down and
sort of take those apart more and
uh
i guess related to that i i should add i
think this group has been so good at
taking apart the ideas of the book this
is perhaps
one of the most effective settings i've
seen for
really
ringing
concepts out of a text and uh you know
the work that's going on with the coda
to build up the ontology and take apart
the equations and things like that i
think is is just tremendous
awesome thank you like
yeah it's um
you know the british call them maths
plural
instead of math as an area and it really
does engage
like
there's visual formalisms which could be
represented with a sparsity matrix or it
could be represented with other um
ways
but there there are um
almost like a multi-scale diversity of
formalisms ranging from more traditional
equal sign in the middle mathematics
to
fusion
schematic equation graphics
um
different types of notations even within
the equation
um
and the difficulty
is
not
signaled not that it has to be but the
difficulty
does
provide a little whiplash sometimes
because
it moves
variously in the main thread of the text
the boxes and the appendices
from like
this is how linear algebra works and
this is what bayes
theorem is
all the way to
topics that are approaching physics
flows on partitioned states
various kinds of fundamental or like in
principle relationships about
mathematics generally
all the way to
postulated
architectures
where message passing is implemented
to achieve some computational function
and or
thread the needle with resembling neural
computational architectures
the math is doing a lot
many things are happening and and so
it's um
only to be expected that the perception
is
challenging
and
there's probably a lot more to even
say
and um
unpack there
anyone else want to raise their hands
and
give a thought on this
section one area
jf and then anyone else
have kind of a general question about
the limits
of mathematics
the notion of computational
irreducibility
uh
that
you have to
go through every step of a process
to get at state and plus 1 from
state and from state and minus whatever
that
certain problems cannot be
solved
by plugging values into a formula and
generating
a future state you have to compute all
the intermediate states
i wonder
where that
fits in in this picture
are there hard limits to the application
of of of mathematics
um to to to the problem of active
inference it's just a general question
returning to some um earlier
comments on
the firm conceptual ground
what
is an area no matter how
narrow or distal from actin where people
believe that
there is
a firm conceptual ground they felt like
that provided a foundation for them to
learn further
are we seeking an analogy
to some other
field of theory or practice or domain
or are we kind of seeking for a
epistemic
territory that we haven't quite
scene
i'll
just add i think that what in active
inference what you're talking about
there jeff is literally blankets
and uncertainty
like the corollary there of like
computational irreducibility
is that there's some large amount of
uncertainty in states in the world that
you're just never going to get at
the blanket is in some sense
not just
how you're relating to it
but some
hard
limit on your
you know your surprisal and
things like that so
thanks
uh brock had written oh yes mike please
uh so responding to the question about
maybe adjacent spacex or spaces or topic
areas
uh i think there's certainly overlap
with
concepts from system dynamics and
certainly a lot of agent-based modeling
has been applied
uh
to model systems that have feedback
loops and
adaptation things like that
we discussed
during the the past weeks relationships
with reinforcement learning and
um
i think there's
a belief that active inference kind of
cleans up some of the challenging
or maybe not challenging but uh
less formalized or less defined aspects
related to reinforcement learning
such as uh how do you engineer a utility
function that makes sense in the context
of what you're trying to model
banks agreed about creating a uh
integrated utility function
there's so many
unprincipled not to say ineffective or
not even to say not elegant but
unprincipled methods of creating
a chimera utility model
like
delay discounting
novelty bonus curiosity bonuses
alternating phases
or hyper parameters
that
um as well as purely implementational
strategies like
discarding burn in
parallel chains there's like
a whole toolkit and indeed fields
on creating
effectively
integrated utility models
and
putting that work
into the construction of the generative
model
and how the generative model is
partitioned from the generative process
allows
a generic free energy functional or set
of related free energy formulations
to play that role
so that's one very interesting angle
as well as
the way that that process of specifying
the generative model and generative
processes and so on
are
world models
whether
in the john le
sense
or in the atom saffron sense
these generative models encompass world
models and deep learning approaches and
various
topics like
that um
so
let's see
blue
wrote i wish there was practice problems
in the book to develop our understanding
yes
um
to a large extent and also it's whether
people want to reflect on any specific
questions or even just on this
um
scheme
these are many of these questions
these questions can be
um
open
infinite game type questions
about the material
they can be clearly addressable
questions about the material
they can be
um
checks for understanding
but we'll be continuing to develop and
improve and
curate questions around the material
so i
[Music]
think it's a great comment
and
this is why we have this future textbook
groups
and all of these affordances for people
to stay involved and and be improving
this as well as experimenting in their
own
spaces and ways
to to develop the kinds of material that
are helping them
learn and understand
any more section one
overview thoughts
chapters one through five
and the framing of the book
being that the first five chapters are
more focused on the conceptual
background
and the second five chapters
are going to be
starting with a recipe for designing the
active models and and getting more into
the modeling itself
so any
section one through five
commentary
the book comprises two parts page three
these are aimed at readers who want to
understand active inference
first part
and those who seek to use it for their
own research second part
the first part of the book introduces
active inference
both conceptually and formally
contextualizing it within current
theories of cognition
how
did they succeed
and where was there a divergence between
what you
preferred
a priori or now
comprehensive formal and self-contained
introduction to active inference
its main constructs and implications for
the study of brain and cognition
i'm uh i'm interested in the distinction
between uh
understanding active inference and using
it
for our own research
and the way that that's set up as those
being two completely separate things
um
it seems to suggest that one could fully
understand active inference and yet not
be in a position to use it in their own
research
not having worked through the second
half of the book and i think that's
quite interesting
it is
good comment thank you
um
[Music]
not to uh spoil the ending
but the last sentence is ultimately we
are confident that you will continue to
pursue active inference in some form
there may be a multi-year
incubation
for different people and contexts
many people
now or even in some
amazing decentralized science future
they may not think of themselves as
researchers or of doing research
though they may be even included on
research projects
um
so it's it's very interesting uh
comments
about
how they
distinguish like
theory and learning
from
[Music]
part two
research and practice
however
um
[Music]
they
discuss applications
but this isn't
the playbook it's not the toolkit
it's not the modeling tool ecosystem
mike
yeah that's an interesting comment at
the end
and
i know this is my perceptual bias but
there seems to be this implicit
assumption that
active inference is the way to go
basically this is the tool to use
within the text
and
so as a result what's not there is a
discussion of
uh maybe these are cases where you might
not want to use active inference or
these are cases where applying active
entrance could create challenges in what
you're solving for
ali and anyone else
and in fact one of the uh most popular
criticisms puts toward the active
inference or fep in general is that
it tries to explain everything
it ends up explaining nothing
so
yeah i think there's a risk of
maybe
not sufficiently constraining the
problem space or
leaving things undefined in a way that
uh
allow for
active interest to be the solution
without a critical point of view
they
highlight
behavior and cognition i mean one could
almost see even
the name active inference as being
a synthesis
of
action
behavior
and cognition
inference
in ways that as we're
discovering and and unpacking
they're integrated in ways that other
formalisms of
perception as a type of cognition so we
can just lump it there
other frameworks of behavior and
cognition
[Music]
have not integrated or have approached
from a
non-first principles
or maybe they do follow first principles
like the higher the impact factor the
better the paper
something like that that's the first
principle
um
no just kidding um
but
placing it within the framework of
cognition
while also
surfing on a wave
of
something like pan cognitivism or like
pan
[Music]
it computationalism
expand the scope
and that's even before
one starts to enter into the more recent
research
especially
where there is a highlight on system
persistence
not simply in terms of the resistance to
dissipation
entropically
but in a relational context as repeated
measurements like in the quantum work
so
it's like
cognition oh like brains like that
schema with a brain or with like a
person
well oh by cognition
it's any system
[Music]
with a blanket
that we're interacting with through
repeated measurement
is that cognition where did cognition go
brock
i am
i
kind of want to i guess echo all those
things that were just said about the
common criticism and this
where does it apply where does it not
apply but
also i guess
um all those things that you were just
listing like i i wonder
i always hear that from people that have
not um
engaged with the material
um
and from
my engagement with it it seems like
all of the examples in which it is used
it are
um
complex dynamical systems that don't
have great that have at best
mathematical approximations and have
almost no or literally no kind of
analytical
approaches
it just seems like a good way to model a
system of things of entities that are
interacting
um
and i don't i i guess what i'm
to to put it into like one question like
what is uh is that kind of some
anthropomorphizing
or whatever projecting
of like
well it's applied to this it's applied
to that
it must apply to everything and um you
know how can it apply to all those
things how can it apply everywhere it's
like it's not applying to everywhere
it's just applying to these
complex systems which are
everywhere
but also don't have and you know we're
not trying to model the apple falling
from the tree or the hyper you know the
these sorts of simple cases or something
it's not being applied there
i mean is it i don't i haven't seen
actually you know now that i think about
it any
of those sorts of situations or it's
applied
to things that we already understand in
this like maybe in some back-checking
way but not in a like way that's
suggested that we should use this much
more complex
you know approach to something that's
kind of
check already got that
you know
um
thanks brock um
ali i kind of feel that uh some of these
criticisms uh
stems from some from the fact from a
serious
a lack of deep understanding of uh
concepts related to fap and active
inference
for example uh i came across
a phd thesis just today
uh
in which
it tries to
critique
everything related to mark of blanket
but
as i was glancing over it uh
i
i observed some serious
uh gaps uh in our argument throughout
all and all the whole the thesis and
i think uh materials such as this book
uh can definitely help in filling up
these gaps of understanding
which even
the
the serious researchers
are suffering from
yes thanks
so to um
this thread
i've never heard it about the linear
model
how could the linear model be used in so
many settings
it explains nothing
well is the linear model an explanation
or is it an investigative tool
in the investigators toolbox
so
at least for me personally doesn't need
to have
broader reach than those who
resonate with it but
again i always try to ask
would somebody say this or could they
say that about a linear model
and then if the actin formalism
with
f equals
dot or g equals
dot
and all of the predicates that it's
associated with and the partition and
all of that
could someone say that about y equals mx
plus b
and then if not and there may be cases
where it is not the same
what is it that's different about active
inference
or
is it
a valid and important and even
reasonable question
but one that might be bumping up like
what jf raised about computational
irreducibility
or about map territory
even
disguised or camouflaged questions about
relationality
well how can complexity science apply to
so many topics
we're applying complexity science to
whatever topic we want to
where's the issue
mike and then ron
yeah a lot of it hinges on
how the model is to be applied and what
the intent of
model application is so
taking the linear model as an example we
might use something like that
to be predictive about a linear system
and so there's potential value there
uh when we do system dynamics models
a lot of times the value in doing a
system dynamics model is aligning the
stakeholders around
what are the model components and how do
we think about those model components so
working through a process similar to
like what we've done in this textbook
group although few do it as rigorously
to
identify the system elements and how
they interact and interrelate and so
forth and and that can lead to
more advanced implementation like
agent-based models
um
but a lot of times at least in my
experience those agent-based models are
used for
deeper systems understanding more than
say predictive power for
what the system is going to do at some
point in the future so
again it comes back to the
the reason for applying the models and
thinking about how the model fits with
that reason and what sort of results you
would expect from that
thank you mike ron
uh yeah i i generally agree with
what you and mike said
so from a practitioner's perspective
uh
i mean we do hear criticisms of
linear models right it's not that we
don't
but it's usually about which domain is
being applied in
uh
yeah uh
but generally speaking
well uh let me close this with uh
because active inference is probably
more
complex and it takes a lot more time to
drop than y equals mx plus b which could
be
one reason for these kind of
criticisms and it's probably
like that they're falling back into old
habits okay why should i jump my old
model
as opposed to adopting this newer more
uh
well how much more does it explain than
what i hope
i think that
probably is driving a lot of the
criticism
of these things
thank you
i can't help but add a domain specific
example
um this is a 2016 paper
that is speaking to like a multi-decade
multi-career
brouhaha
about
different approaches to modeling
evolution and selection
for example in the eu social insects and
in social animals as well
and this article is very fascinating
because
they use a bayesian causal graph
to identify situations where
two different formulations
the kin and the multi-level selection
models
have identical predictions
where the causal graphs have identical
predictions
any measurement
you can think of as being like on a y
equals x manifold where it doesn't
resolve your uncertainty about which
framework is correct or not
yet the literature is littered with we
measured these ovaries
so can selection is or isn't happening
however a vast set of those empirical
cases
might be
essentially falling on this manifold
where those two models are not
distinguishable
and so
this is a theory driven approach like a
first principles approach
to identify situations
that
are
providing unique informative value
in this case about
canon multi-level selection
and knowing what territories
measurements will not have explanatory
value
which
relates to active inference um
just like rohan and like many people
have brought up especially when we
kind of take like a meta science or like
a communicating science or onboarding
people into active concern
like people are asking
explicitly or implicitly why should i
update my cognitive model
what is the value of active inference
can you
appetize me
with a two minute video
so i can understand it
or with a two minute video so it's
enough to want to continue going down
that path
there's a lot to say and there's um
[Music]
a lot of work
to identify
the situations
and the ways of truly addressing and
perhaps even resolving
[Music]
long-standing
scientific divergences
like
if it is the case that the explore
exploit dialectic
is addressed in a novel way
through the free energy functional
balancing pragmatic and epistemic reward
that is
quite a vast scope
people continue to use explore and
exploit today
and it is the evident that that those
ontology terms wouldn't be useful in the
future
in fact
some of the
um
discussions on like folk psychology with
the belief desires intentions
can we say what an active inference
entity wants
or intends based upon its beliefs and
its desires for example
can we still talk about exploratory and
exploitative behavior
as a phenomena but have a different way
of modeling how that behavior arises or
or is
regulated
what are the settings in
behavioral cognitive science
where systems dynamics has been applied
where we can now use active
inference to identify
where have we been just
throwing a thousand darts
at
the same
grain of sand
where are the vast
fields
where we don't even know
and as people have highlighted the book
is written
with a specific rhetorical
bent both explicitly and implicitly
um
for the regime of attention of the book
to be about active inference
one can read as an implicit endorsements
that this is something that is
valid or valuable to pursue
and
especially at this stage in the field it
is almost like an exhortation
to
persist amidst uncertainty
to learn and apply
few disjointed thoughts there but
i hope it makes sense
let's look back to the subjections of
the book
anyone can raise their hand or give a
thought like
how
could
the book you write
begin
what reviewer comments
whether you're reviewer one reviewer two
reviewer three
what comments would you have provided if
this were like
a draft
and you could even make structural
suggestions
so i have a lot of comments there
yes blue and then ron
um i uh
so like
having taught
lots of classes before like i think um
a list of like key terms and definitions
would be like critical i mean i mean and
like
learning objectives for each chapter
um
like i said uh like a practice quiz like
test your knowledge of this like like
what is surprise like how many different
forms of surprise are there you know i
mean like like just some practice
questions to see if you grasped the
concepts prevented in each chapter
um
and especially like uh what i was
mentioning in the chat like math
problems like practice like can you set
up your own generative model um like
like what would the like or even just
the bayesian graph like can you make a
bayesian graph like what would that look
like for you know give a give a question
like a verbal description and then
give the bayesian graph like answer or
like make the answers available online
so you could test your own knowledge of
the subject first um i think that that
would be like totally instrumental in in
using this functionally like a textbook
anyway so sorry
thanks blue nice predictive programming
rohan and then
brock uh yeah uh so
my
as a practitioner right i
work in the engineering field i'm a
control systems engineer
my preference would be to immediately
see some application
not necessarily to control systems but
something that it begins with
like a project and explains how active
inference is better than its own
baseline
that would be
interesting to see
uh like a perfect example of this would
be
i don't know if you've heard of fastai
by rachel thomas and jeremy howard they
have a very unique way of teaching
uh
so they have a computational linear
algebra course so the way they teach the
linear algebra part is by basically
implementing gaussian blur for example
and then connecting it to
so you start with the code and then you
do the math then you connect it to the
math
so something like that
might be far more useful
uh maybe not from a
point but it would
definitely be useful for practitioners
around the world okay so this
so if you know controls engineer gets
this okay this looks like a better form
model predictive control i can replace
my model predictive controller with
something
that resembles active inference
it might actually make uh
we might actually make more progress
that it actually gets out of the way
thank you ron brock
um
yeah i i think i mean i've had
similar comments to that of um
you know
fast ai and
benchmarks that that's kind of the
ultimate
way that's just the way that um
practitioners change their um attention
now
um and that would be really useful but
in in the context of the book
um
i think i agree with every everything
else that was said too uh
i'm not sure how realistic it is to do
that from
the point you know where
the whole
field is at right now sorry about that
um
but
you know
i think
just having some some things in context
like there's always this comment about
like
you know it's a non-linear thing a text
is linear so of course it'll be out of
out of order
but like um
often the definitions of things are
kind of scattered throughout the
explanation of them
and
kind of
italicize instead of kind of brought up
to the top you know
in some
um
way you might expect
that i at least from my
my
pedagogical experience everything like
all math is
taught to you know
like to define your knowns and unknowns
and variables at the top and the sort of
thing right um
the in the
context of like the appendices
um
again there's like
i understand that
it's a lot you can't you know do you
can't add that all in or whatever but
just
if there was like
um either every whenever
the next part of the appendice became
relevant
you know um again just like having it at
the top like at each section you're like
okay so we're gonna use part you know
now building on you know what we've done
already like now we're going to use this
part of this this section in the
appendices in this section our equation
one two three whatever
in
in in this next section like just
stating it up front
again just like a like a you know
big box on the top or whatever
um
it just
would help like in wayfinding and
disentangling
the
unfortunate linear um
format of books
that is mapped to this complex thing um
and so
[Music]
yeah i don't know those those general
things would be helpful one other thing
that is maybe beyond the scope of this
book but
um spoke to ellie about very briefly at
one point about the notation
like even in the basic example of the
frog here
um like bayesian notation
it's um
it's incredibly easy to manipulate
variables when they're
one letter and subscripts
but when the whole variable is like 10
or 20 letters like
you know frog p p of x equals frog jump
you know condition on a y it's like it
becomes a larger
i don't i don't know if this is just me
and dyslexic you know like i don't know
but um it just seems harder to
cognitively kind of
um work with that
um
i don't know thank you brock
yes the chunking is multi-level
and there it will be great to explore
ways to um
learn around that
here
are a few
forays where we can copy quotes and have
inline definitions
so for those who are interested in this
kind of
work
with an open source textbook
it is not an infinite task or even a
non-automatable task
to copy out the plain text
and integrate it with a versioning
ontology
so that the definition
can be like
even rendered differently it could be in
a different language it could be every
single time that a term comes up
there's like
so much enrichment
that this seed
can lead to
of the textbook
and
a lot of it is for
us to pick up
honestly
rohan and then anyone else
oh i i forgot to put down
oh no worries thank you
so in our um
last seven or so minutes for this
session
next week
we will continue with any
conceptual points and questions that
people want to raise
we'll also be
turning our attention
a bit more
to
uh making sure first off that please
please everyone complete the feedback
form
in the future textbook groups and or
add information here or um contact us
because
it's just one of the most important
feedback mechanisms we have
we'll also be exploring a little bit
different
project
ideas
um
several of these threads involving
different system models
we've already found
a home for
in the active block prints project
where we're
meeting
twice on wednesdays weekly
other
projects
we're going to have new vistas on during
and after
going through the second half of the
textbook
which
is uh still black and white static pdfs
but we'll be able to augment this
heavily
with some
simulation tools
as well as
other
work like
the plain text enrichment or even anyone
who wants to collaborate on an audiobook
version
there's um
no lack of
act imp
tasks
today
and these are like
high leverage point
moments
where staying in the game and improving
the game will do tremendous service
towards reducing research debt and
improving the rigor and the applications
that we see
rohan
yeah uh can i make a project suggestion
that's fine yes please
everyone can yeah so that
yeah okay so there is uh i'm gonna put
this in the chat there's this online lab
by georgia tech's intelligence
assistance unit
uh called robutario
uh that's basically a bunch of swarm
it's to test swamp controllers
so uh there's a good baseline over here
it would be a good idea to try like an
active inference version
like an active inference inspired swamp
controller
to finish the tasks over here
so this runs on actual robots
in that lab
and you can see the results
this is awesome um
i had
some
colleagues who worked with
some of the ant groups here
it's right at the intersection of
like
jf's work and many's interest in
embodied and robotic angle
and we have
somewhat
extensive
um
multi-scale generative models
of ants
which would apply to other swarm
settings as well so absolutely
um
we
want to scaffold those projects and
one way to start but not the only way to
start
is to
copy a version of this
these fields and add and remove as
relevant for you
and give some
um
handle
for others to be involved or just
stay in the game
so that um
more people can join there will be a
flow of people entering active inference
forever
how will we greet them
so uh what would i need to put in
um
like
it depends on how you want to carry
forward the project but you can feel in
this row add any
notes you'd like
and um
more details on what you're thinking of
doing
and then however you want to be more
specific about like
directions
and
just signal it in the idea
or you can in the um notes or or draft
catechism
which is what these templates are
based on
and if there is ever something you're
not
sure about then
ask around and um
different projects are going to
proceed
differently
okay yeah uh so i'll fill that out
with my talk
so awesome
well
interesting meeting
it's our penultimate discussion in this
section
then we hope that
everybody who is
motivated and
ready to do so
continues for part two
and or rejoins for part one cohort two
both of these will be starting in
september
so we'll take august
um off of the textbook
and
uh at this point the tentative plan is
that we'll have
two sequential hours
like
section one
and then followed by section two
so that those who are on section one
can um
see how
section two is
we can explore different architectures
and stuff and again this is like why
people's active participation and their
feedback
and the over sharing
on topic
and just writing all the questions that
came in their mind and all the things
that they would want to ask somebody to
check like
every contribution is important
does anyone else have any
thing they'd like to add before we stop
the recording
okay
stopping the recording
oh yeah someone go for it
all right stopping the recording